ryot.org 2015-11-02

# Privacy Policy - RYOT News

**RYOT’S PRIVACY POLICY**

Welcome to RYOT! RYOT Corp (“ **RYOT** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **us** ,” or “ **our** ”) operates this website (www.RYOT.org) (the “ **Site** ”) as well as a number of related services (collectively, the “ **Services** ”). The focus of our Site and Service is to provide readers with a destination to find out what’s going on in the world AND what can be done about it. Privacy is of great importance to us and we have established this privacy policy as a means to communicate our information collection, use and dissemination practices.

So we are clear on the terminology we use, “ **Personal Information** ” means contact information (e.g., your name, address, email address, and/or telephone number) and any other non-public information that is used or intended to be used to personally identify an individual, and any other non-public information that is associated with that information. “Anonymous Information” means information that is not used or intended to be used to personally identify an individual.

**BY USING OUR SITE OR SERVICES OR SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION THROUGH OUR SITE OR SERVICES, YOU AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT AND YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION ACCORDING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED BY US IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AS WELL AS OTHER COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY.**

**Children**.  
The Site and Services are not directed to children and children are not eligible to use our Services. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. We do not collect Personal Information from people we actually know are under 13 years of age. If we later learn that a user is under 13 years of age, we will take steps to prevent the user from utilizing the Site and the Services.

**COLLECTED INFORMATION**  
You are not required to provide any Personal Information to use our Site or Services. We only collect Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily. For example, if you communicate with us through our Site or by sending us an email, we may collect and store any information that is contained in your communications with us. In general, the Personal Information we gather enables us to provide the Services to you.

 _Any donation you make on the Site is made through Crowdrise, our third party donation platform, and we are not involved in this donation transaction_

. We do not take a fee or receive any information associated with your transaction, other than your email address, which you provide to both our provider and to us. Similarly, if you wish to provide comments for content on the Site or share content via email with your friends or contacts, we use a third party provider to provide you and other users with that functionality. Any Personal Information you provide through these features will not be collected by us – even for comments that may appear on our Site. Please review the privacy policy of our service providers prior to providing any Personal Information, and please be careful when disclosing Personal Information about yourself.

 _Anonymous Information_

We collect the following types of Anonymous Information:

_Information Collected by Our Servers_. To make our Site and Services more useful to you, our servers (which may be hosted by a third party service provider) collect information from you, including your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (“ **IP** ”) address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet, which may vary from session to session), domain name, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit.

_Log Files_. As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (“ **ISP** ”), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users’ movements around the Site, gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and better tailor our Services to our users’ needs. For example, some of the information may be collected so that when you visit the Site or the Services again, it will recognize you and the information could then be used to serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests.

_Cookies_. Like many online services, we use cookies to collect information. “ **Cookies** ” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing the website. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our Site. This type of information is collected to make the Site more useful to you and to tailor the experience with us to meet your special interests and needs. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to accept cookies from our Service for any of the purposes described above, then you can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. Consult your browser’s technical information. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Services or all functionality of the Services.

_Collection of Information by Advertisers_. We may use third parties to serve ads on the Site. Certain third parties may automatically collect information about your visits to this and other websites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit our Site (but not your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number). They do this by using Cookies or other technologies. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Site and the other sites tracked by these third parties. This policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, Cookies or pixel tags in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of Cookies and other technologies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.

_Disclosure – Third Party Cookies_  
We use third party services such as Google Analytics to help analyze how users use the Site. These services use Cookies to collect information such as how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the information we get from these service providers to improve our Site and Services. They generally collect only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit the Site or Services, rather than your name or other personally identifying information. We do not combine this information with your Personal Information. The service provider’s ability to use and share information it collects is restricted by its applicable terms and privacy policy.

**USE OF INFORMATION**

 _Personal Information_

– We will use your Personal Information to:  
– Administer your Account;  
– Provide you with Services and customer support;  
– Market to you our products and services (and those of third parties) that we believe may interest you;  
– Respond to your requests, resolve disputes and/or troubleshoot problems;  
– Verify your compliance with your obligations in our Terms of Use or other RYOT policies;  
– Improve the quality of the Site and the Services; and  
– Communicate with you about the Site and the Services.

We may also use your Personal Information to create Anonymous Information records by excluding information that makes the information personally identifiable to you.

We will communicate with you primarily in the form of emails. You can manage the frequency and/or opt out of receiving these communications by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email.

 _Anonymous Information_

Generally, we use Anonymous Information in statistical analysis to help us analyze patterns in the use of our Services. We may, through our use of Cookies, keep you logged into our Site, collect your click-stream data, tailor web content to you and personalize your experience on the Site. We may also use your Anonymous Information to improve our internal operations, notify visitors of updates to our Site and Services, and software and customize the content and layout of the Site and/or Service.

**DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION**

 _Personal Information_

– We may disclose certain Personal Information:  
– To third party vendors who help us provide the Services or the Site;  
– To third parties to whom you ask us to send Personal Information;  
– To a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “Affiliates”), in the event we have such Affiliates in the future, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy;  
– In connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets. In the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, Personal Information may also be transferred as a business asset. If another company acquires our company, business, or assets, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy; or  
– If we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) resolve disputes, investigate problems, or enforce our Terms of Use; (b) comply with relevant laws or to respond to requests from law enforcement or other government officials relating to investigations or alleged illegal activity, in which case we can (and you authorize us to) disclose Personal Information without subpoenas or warrants served on us; or (c) protect and defend our rights or property or the rights and property of you or third parties.

We provide functionality operated by third-parties that enables a number of public forums on the Site. Please remember that you are welcome to share as much Personal Information as you think is necessary and appropriate, but that any Personal Information and content of posts you make that appear on our Site will be made available to our third party service provider, as well as generally on our Site.

In addition, some of our Services may enable you to post content to social networking services (e.g., Facebook or Twitter) (“ **SNS** ’). If you choose to do this, we will provide information to such SNSs in accordance with your elections. You acknowledge and agree that you are solely responsible for your use of those websites and that it is your responsibility to review the terms of use and privacy policy of the third party provider of such SNSs. We will not be responsible or liable for: (i) the availability or accuracy of such SNSs; (ii) the content, products or services on or availability of such SNSs; or (iii) your use of any such SNSs.

 _Anonymous Information_

We may disclose Anonymous Information without restriction.

**FEEDBACK**  
If you provide feedback to us, we may use and disclose such feedback for any purpose, provided we do not associate such feedback with your Personal Information. We will collect any information contained in such feedback and will treat the Personal Information in it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Accessing and Controlling your Information**.  
You can review and/or change any of your Personal Information by emailing us at info@ryot.org. You authorize us to use and disclose any new or modified information that you provide in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please remember, however, if we have already disclosed some of your Personal Information to third parties, we cannot access that Personal Information any longer and cannot force the deletion or modification of any such information by the parties to whom we have made those disclosures.

Upon your request, we will delete any Personal Information you have provided to us, except that we may retain your Personal Information to comply with laws, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

**Information Disclosed to Third Parties**  
This Privacy Policy addresses only our use and disclosure of information we collect from and/or about you. If you disclose information to others or otherwise on our Site, the use and disclosure restrictions contained in this Privacy Policy will not apply to any third party and we encourage you to review the privacy policies of those third parties. We do not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable.

The Site or Services may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by us. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other websites. When you click on such a link, you will leave our Site or Services and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect Personal Information or Anonymous Information from you.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**.  
This Privacy Policy is subject to revision from time to time on a going-forward basis. We will post any revised version of the Privacy Policy on this page. If we make any material changes to it, we will also send you notice thereof to the last email address you have provided to us. Continued use of our Services following notice of such changes will indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

**Contact Us**.  
If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us by sending an email to: info@ryot.org.

This Policy was last revised: June 17, 2014
